[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard hello
hello welcome to the junkyard love
podcast today's recommendation before
said podcast is going to be another
podcast that I like to listen to this
podcast is from evolutionary biologist
bread weinstein he actually lives in
Portland if that tickles your fancy I'm
just gonna read the description of the
Dark Horse podcast real quick it's just
desirable I think you guys would enjoy
it if you like my podcast you like more
intelligent people talking about more
intelligent things in the same manner on
the Dark Horse podcast we will explore
questions that matter with tools that
work many episodes will be long-form
discussions some guests will be well
known others obscure but although all of
them chosen because they have
demonstrated unusual insight other
episodes of The Dark Horse podcast will
be solo missions in which Brett dives
into issues alone using an
evolutionarily using an evolutionary
lens to reveal patterns in nature
including human nature the state and
future of civilization will be
reoccurring theme so buckle up sounds
great right check that out brett
weinstein dark dark horse podcast also
please like comment subscribe all those
sort of things really do help me out
just just share if you enjoyed if it's
good content if you if you benefit from
it just share and if you aren't drinking
water are you out of your mind what are
you doing you haven't drank water in a
while has it been
is there no water next to right now is
it where's the nearest water cup to you
when's the last time you took a drink of
it
come on listener drink some water
alright let's roll here's the episode
running a lot Spencer
I feel very thin I did so when I was in
Lake Shasta
I like cuz it's like I know that we're
gonna drink hot we did our true it's
just like the time that I know you know
let's prep it's prep for it so I woke up
every morning and I ran like it was like
30 flights and elevation in like four
miles every morning you know I've liked
it I'm saying that not to brag but just
because it's like impressive that I'm
continuously
doing it and so it's just getting easier
like it's not like a difficult or easy
thing even it's just a thing that I do
at this point with with running already
so it's just a [__] cool place to be
we have been running a lot and then I've
been eating I have a shake every day
with lots of mushrooms in collagen or
your suggestion and healthy greens and I
think that these things are actually
like thinning me out I think it's
helping my digestion a ton my
inflammation is down from some of the
mushroom powders my cardiovascular is up
from some of the mushroom powders yeah
it's so good if you try course ups yet
to run a yes I think that's one of them
that I'm taking is that cardiovascular
that's yeah yeah yeah cordyceps help you
utilize oxygen better and like you take
it before you run you'll be noticed
you'll have noticed Lee better endurance
oh yeah I in and I and I so when I get
gassed I can bring myself back with a
slow heart rate in 30 seconds it's
pretty [__] sick feels good yeah but
is there so the thing about mushroom
powders I mean lions made does kind of
give you like it's not a buzz at all but
it's if you've if you're not familiar
with like a head change you might feel
like a little uptick with lion's mane
for sure or if I don't know maybe people
feel like a big uptick but other than
that the other ones you know for
inflammation and in cordyceps and stuff
I don't really feel too different like
cognitive wise so it's cool to feel you
know like your body my body feels good
it's a thing that we don't really have
connection with like we don't really
know when we're feeling inflamed because
we're just our brain feels crappy too
but when your body is loose and not
inflamed your brains feeling norm
it's nice to you or if you're just
inflamed all the time you never know
just it's just how you are I think that
everybody is inflamed all the time
come on over son yeah feel like that's
not a plane a scratch any listener who
doesn't really know that they're
inflamed or they don't really know much
my information give give me like a
one-minute information like why is it
bad or what is it why does it happen
yeah start explaining them five
information what's up with it
so usually inflammation good thing your
body uses the healing process so like
okay you got a bruise you get blood flow
to the area it inflames it swells up and
you get fresh nutrients to it but when
you're chronically inflamed from like
dietary choices it can happen in a lot
of ways one of the really common ones is
um well poor sleep it happens and a you
need a ratio of omega-6 to omega-3 fatty
acids so like I make it through
something like fish and omega-6 is
around like french fries like bad bad
fats essentially and one of the when you
get swayed too far to omega-6 is you
become chronically inflamed I mean
people will notice like like um like my
wrists will hurt your feet will hurt
just kind of for no reason you love like
a very puffy face puffy under eyes like
you loaded yeah if you've ever become
not inflamed and then become inflamed
again you'll notice it isn't terrible my
fingers well if you ever if you wear
rings you definitely feel it in your
hands a lot of times I did anyway yeah
and then you'll begin to hold
extracellular water so you want to hold
water in the cells like in your muscles
or in like just your cells in general
and when you're holding it outside of it
it just causes all these things but this
can cause I'm usually like brain
inflammation it's where it's bad because
it causes like a cognitive downtick I
mean almost every single chronic disease
is linked back to inflammation mm-hmm
like Alzheimer's is an inflammatory
disease like heart disease can be to
some degree so you know as you explain
this to me I find myself just like I was
thinking like why the [__] is this not
the most known thing like why isn't it
taught like why instead of watching like
the Dems slam the Lib tardes why aren't
people who were watching on TV telling
us how to reduce inflammation like why
aren't we concentrating on [__] like
this like why don't people know the same
thing with the
coronavirus like nobody was saying
here's how you get healthier though
let's strengthen those immune systems
guys we don't know [__] about this thing
but let's come together here's what I
know about information we're gonna get
all the top US doctors 150 of them in a
room and they're gonna do a conference
oh well not in room eight that probably
like bad idea but because ooh meaning
and zoom meetings but it's it's
ridiculous that you know these things
are actually pretty important like I I
don't think that I guess you know it's
not like our parent my parents didn't
know essentially and they still like
don't know like they they wouldn't know
about this but I just think it should be
normal
taught instead we're taught the
Kellogg's food guide pyramid yeah so now
we got to take a step back and look at
the incentive of media and government
when it comes to health and as we have a
57 56 % of adults are obese did you say
that's not even counting morbidly obese
which is like a smaller segment of the
population that's in that but we do not
it's just not a priority it doesn't make
money like people Lobby our education
you know the news is not a tool to make
your life better it's a tool of control
right so what like there's no if you're
gonna fill 24-hours a news cycle like
they don't give a [__] if you're
inflamed or not they just want you to
pay attention right like they don't want
you to feel better and they want you to
feel how they feel exactly yeah so
they're it's very unfortunate especially
like us I mean I guess I am a health
professional I mean that's sounds cooler
than it is I'm a personal trainer but to
see people just like everyone owns a
body like you pilot a meat vehicle you
do like why you should know how to
operate optimally like you know like you
know you need to put oil in your car and
do all these things like basic
maintenance like why don't people know
how to do that for the body mm-hmm and
it's hard to see but I mean it does make
it really rewarding to tell people but
the fact that like nobody's told them
before they're 40 when I see them it
feels really bad it's like you could
have been living so much more optimally
and felt so much better for so long if
somebody would just told you this and
this is readily available information
that just nobody is peddling yeah this
is dude it feels important to me like
the older I get the more I look back at
like man since I was however many it
like there's my particular life I had to
learn so much on my own just my whole
life has been do-it-yourself so for me
like even nutrition
like like learning about what's good for
you and I feel like everybody is stuck
with that everybody is like stuck with
we'll just go to the internet and try to
figure it out but then there's all these
ads that are fed to us there's all this
blah blah blah in in in our brain
something I go on a lot about on like my
Instagram story is is the way we think
about our bodies and in health and
weight and I don't like scales and in a
unless you're someone who's actively
trying to get specific goals on way it's
like why do you care so much about
weight and what about feeling good what
about eating foods oh is this gonna make
me fat so I can't fit into that swimsuit
for the vacation no [__] that [__] that
care about what's gonna make you feel
good and if you feel good every day from
what you're eating you know a symptom of
that is you may be gonna lose some
weight yeah but the the the way that
we're kind of forced to look at
everything like from a young age like
you know like if you're forced to go to
oh yeah I don't know I think the our
perception of our own bodies is not in
our own control and it feels important
to me to at every step that I can since
I've all this crap that I've learned and
failed at and tried to learn and fail
that to like get people to talk about it
and get people to like kind of learn
like oh maybe I don't know that much
about health or maybe I'm looking at it
in a different code be looking at a
different way or I don't know I don't
see kids who are like 10 years old right
now like they should be growing up by
the time they're 15 and they should know
everything that I know in a good way
okay great awesome yeah I guess we gotta
take a step back and figure out why it
is the way it is you know there's no I
mean you look at the medical industry
there's no money and wellness money and
symptoms and people like it's so hard to
parse information because people are
trying to sell you things like there's
monetary gain involved so and like oh
I'll get on the internet figure it out
well if you don't understand how biology
works like your sniff test
like you can't be skeptical because you
don't have the means to be skeptical so
you get marketed by something really
flashy and you buy it and I mean there's
already you I mean the the biggest
problem with that is you're already
looking outward to try to get a cure
even though it's probably a wellness or
a lifestyle thing and then there
also selling you something that isn't
gonna do what you think it's gonna do so
I would say and then again with the
image thing and weight loss like if
you're eating stuff that's gonna make
you feel good you I would bet my life
that you're gonna lose weight if you're
overweight or um like in a a above
healthy body fat range because that
would be a lot of fiber a lot greens
like this stuff is really filling a not
very calorie dense so I mean of course
you're gonna lose weight and I do think
that the the perspective is unacceptable
because we have such a vain society that
culture and just like commercialism just
tries to hey you're without I'm gonna
sell you something that's going to make
you whole here's this supplement rather
than the inverse of that so I think it's
just like a multitude of problems with
American culture and nothing I've ever
been taught was helpful really I had to
figure it all out of my own which is
people don't have time to do that
doesn't seem like like you give me new
Orkut blood people are overworked so
they're forced to eat like [__] I mean
they're not forced to but it's just what
ends up happening and then no one's
gonna help them figure it out and this
is why I mean this might be shameless
plug but I feel like everyone should
have a trainer in a therapist really
hire someone to figure out for you right
I was talking about this and talking
about this wish hailey is I think that
what's going to happen in game B and our
next like whatever is next hopefully
there's not a war in between I'm hoping
that there's some sort of something that
pops up in our world in the next you
know 10 15 years that is before
hospitals because I feel like in our
heads we don't understand the hospitals
in that big building is for like ham
bleeding can you help me sew it up like
that's you know it's for so much more
than that surgeries and so much more of
course but it's for fixing us when we're
broken but like what about optimizing
yourself so you don't get broken as
easily like what why isn't it taught to
people like well okay so so just talk to
people like there's like this general
almost like yelling at an audience
that's not listening if like you guys
you got a stretch you gotta each agree
so you got it like there's that but how
do we like it like how do we actively
create this thing
that is the the personal there's--it's a
therapist and a personal trainer and
like teach you how to take care of this
[__] meet vehicle so you don't hurt
yourself because the food you eat hurts
your brain dude it hurts when you're
inflamed you don't think as clearly when
you're feeling crappy and we're such
societal creatures when when when you're
not when we're not comfortable with our
body we're not able to think about like
like what do I want to do what makes me
happy what uh-ohhhhh like let me
remember to get flowers for my wife
because we're so self-conscious about
being fat like it's it's these long we
don't see things as like a over the
course of a few years like what is the
effects of bad food and not knowing how
to take care of your body and the
importance of you know you know just
having your your breath from your belly
like these sort of things you know I
don't know I'm hoping that there's
something that pops up and helps people
not think they need to just go to
hospitals and then you know like then my
600-pound life is a good example like
you know that that's that's [__] so
sad that those people didn't know or
they they they didn't have help with
their addictions or habits I mean
obviously this is ending the ending
world hunger of course anybody would
want this but I don't know I'm hoping
that there's more smart people that pop
up and make something before hospitals
well I think that uh right now you and I
are both frog sitting in a bucket of
cold water that's slowly boiling like
there is friction rising and you do see
like wellness is becoming a thing like
in that the response to Instagram was in
extreme it was extremely vain and you
see a lot people trying to get very
aesthetically fit but from what I've
seen I mean I've been falling just a
fitness injury for probably nine years
since I've been exercising and wellness
is becoming the pibil of that people
want to move better people want to feel
better and it seems like that it's just
gonna happen like people already have a
massive distress of the medical industry
they don't like hospitals they don't
like doctors they don't want to take a
pill people have an mean look at
vaccines people don't wanna take
medication
if you don't like it people don't like
to take this one thing they don't trust
this industry but if they can go
somewhere else and find this wellness in
this light and personal ubiquity and
just like anything that is non-invasive
its I mean I've seen it in clients even
over the last two years like more and
more people are like do you have any
like herbal supplements that I could
take like like how does breath work work
like what do you do for anxiety and it's
it's been awesome and I really think we
like you said humans are super bad at
looking at things long-term and we
didn't evolve to do that I mean you want
to survive tomorrow not next year so I
really think it's happening yeah yeah
and I have a lot of faith in just the
path of humanity in general even though
it looks so bleak now even with culture
stuff like progressive movements and
people having freedom over time has just
slowly gotten better and better and like
the image of marginalized people will
get better and better and I think that
once we start looking at obesity and not
like it discussed more like hey this is
a symptom of a problem they probably
didn't control because they didn't have
control of their lifestyle factors so
you're gonna get even better mm-hmm
I got a lot of faith man I think it's
gonna be good I think people are like
waking up to the idea of just like man I
want to live my life and feel well right
I mean do you think that I think that I
think that there's a huge search for
meaning you know like you think that's
that's anybody's life purpose right it's
to find their meaning but I think that
there's like this new there's this new
sense of meaning there's this more like
maybe we're more tuned to it or maybe
we're like waking up to you know when
you're feeling like crap all the time
and then all of a sudden you want to
like you know what Dee I'm so sick and
feeling like crap I want to get healthy
there's you know that right there is
enough to spark all those people who are
like I want to I want to learn about
this they're going to have to relook at
like the meaning like what what does it
mean like what do I want why am i eating
healthier like you know and they're
gonna be we're gonna be forced to kind
of look at why we do the things we do
the more that this wellness thing pops
up and I think that that's a good thing
yeah I talk to clients all the time
about like hey why do you want this like
do you think that what what what what
are answers that you get well
usually it's pushed back on like
stricter diets and I always tell people
hey if if living this lifestyle
to get to this point like this is the
toll that you need to do to look like
this and if it's gonna make you if
you're it's gonna detract from your
overall happiness and this obviously if
they're like healthy people they just
want to like have a better physique in
their eyes that this is the toll to get
here and if it's gonna bring you less
happiness to do that then your goal is
gonna bring you happiness then you
shouldn't do it that we should just look
for let's just optimize how you feel and
it maybe it'll come then but I do think
though the why of health is changing and
people like and like anything like you
see people get stopped at their
surroundings like they try to I'm gonna
change my life I want to feel better I'm
gonna do this thing and then everyone
around them is not and they slowly get
tugged back in so I really think I would
love to see a big pulse like we get a
lot of people I mean just like how many
movement starts like it's it's hard when
there's not a lot but when you have a
lot of people behind you it's gonna get
done yeah I think the you know things
like that or what give me you know I try
to keep my faith I try to keep my like
okay you know what like every person
that messages you or every person that
does listen to the podcast like those
you know those are people and that's
their life like the the numbers when
they go up like they're not they're not
a crazy amount but they're it's like
those are people and I'm hoping that
those are ripples and I hope that not
that I'm like a know-it-all and like
like I'm saying the only right answer
that my guests are the only people who
are saying the truth and everything else
is not it's never what I would try to
suggest I'm just saying like the more
that we can see each other as like
brother and sister in like a man like I
didn't choose to be born like I don't
know [__] what's going on either but
like here's what I've learned so far
what have you learned like that's what I
want to like every interaction can be
like that every person you meet could be
like this new just vessel of knowledge
in and I think that you know as where
the internet obviously evolves our brain
man like it I think that a lot a lot
more and more we're seeing people just
bypass the whole like like I'm I don't
even know like we're going underground
or going above the like [__]
like okay I get it catalogs you're
trying to sell me this thing that's why
okay no thanks what is really healthy
you type in you type in on reddit and
then you have people across the world
who are like hey here's what worked for
me it seems like you have this sort of
thing going on I think that when we when
we I don't know so do you think like the
people who are like bypassing like the
why I'm trying to think of like what the
word is like what are we bypassing here
in this analogy it sounds like brands
honestly brands like I mean I want to
say like political like the the wrong
info that they give us the bias info
like the the people who read our history
books that only give us the Americans
bias side I mean yeah I understand
what's it I don't know I mean we're just
kind of the goal is to bypass like dogma
and information that's been filtered
through a viewpoint like if I'm really
like if somebody's really I mean it's
just like you said Kellogg's like no
[__] they're gonna try to sell you
Kellogg's products and people are waking
up with the fact that I think people are
waking up to the idea that most people
are just trying to sell you [__] and not
help you mmm-hmm and beaten like they're
getting kind of tired of it so we're
just not listening to like we're not
falling for flashy branding anymore all
this I hope people aren't and like hey
like looking at this product objectively
is like hey what is this helping me and
then you go talk to other people and
maybe see what they say about it
and it's just not not that one click buy
mentality like people are trying to dig
a little more right I think that's good
questioning why we're doing the things
that we're doing I think why is just a
really important question to ask
not with why not with why yes so right
now let's talk about let's talk about
where we're at in I mean the world for
sure like Australia is just [__] is
Australia so I'm fire and the hotels got
put in them we have you know some
serious [__] the last few days let's
start with that you want to just fill in
just if anybody's listening to this
podcast at a different time you want to
say what's going on
so in Minneapolis I believe one to two
days ago a a black man died because he
was positionally asphyxiated
by the police and a and they go through
training too unlike when you handcuff
someone you don't want to lay them on
their stomach for very long because they
just can't die like that you want to
roll them onto their side like they get
trained for this like it very well
knowledgeable on this thing not me but
I'm saying police are there were
multiple videos that are theirs you can
glean any like content intent from it
which is made it a very weird situation
but this police officer he was suspected
of forging a what is it a check at
target and he surrendered peacefully
didn't resist and he died with the
police officers knee on the back of his
neck after asking saying hey I can't
breathe help hey I can't breathe over
four minutes like this we just went on
and on and this is not the first time
this [__] has happened like that but
this one no [__] like this just happens
every single day yeah it just does this
was on film at this like very like we're
in an unsettled position now I mean
they're there so what so they're riding
yeah I was extremely egregious and you
know every movement like black lives
matter is extremely dismissed by a
certain part of society like all the
peaceful protests and gets dismissed
like no you can't take a knee like why
wouldn't you resolve this somewhere else
like why oh why are you gonna do this so
if you're being marginalized and you're
not being heard peacefully you have one
option you got you you have to do this
you have to at least show some kind of
force and riots don't or riots don't
really start out like looting and
burning the police station but they rev
up and when you have a group of people
that has been just systemically shafted
for so long like this is just what
happens this is what happens and so they
storm the police station and I love this
like there's a big anarchist streak in
me like I am real burn it down kind of
the kind of guy so you see this is how
it always once the people understand
that if they band together there's very
few of them and we are the reason
they're there so they can't do anything
about it so they band up they
raid the police station take all the rag
gear burn it down and they start looting
and looting people are very upset about
looting big corporations like Target
like oh you shouldn't do that and I'm
like if in a capitalist society you
marginalize a lot of people and goods
and services are put above human life
one of the biggest signs of defiance is
to steal goods and services so like that
would be why that's a tactic like that
and like people are just tired of it you
know I mean I'm tired of it like
everyone everyone that is seeing like
african-americans minorities get
marginalized in the country and we have
very tense race relations right now
because of how our government is running
they're just very they've really
scapegoat a lot of minorities it's just
gotten worse and worse like white
supremacy is up like they're sick of it
like priests brutality has been a
problem for a very long time and I'm
frankly I'm really glad to see something
like this happen even though there is
collateral damage that is unacceptable
like when you start to lose like some
businesses like it's it's a mob so some
businesses that are probably privately
owned by good people like do take ahead
but for the greater message I am I'm
glad to see it happen like something
like this needed to happen so what do
you think I agree I think that where my
brain goes is like years in the future
of years in the future with optimism so
what would be we can't keep trying to
squash these bugs as they happen like we
need to like there needs to be an
intelligence brought to the people who
are unaware of their racism or their
there there needs to be something that
because they're you know there's echo
chambers that keep this racism alive
like so what in the future not just
sucks because you just picture the big
arm of the government with too much
technology being a like snuff out who's
who and what they're thinking but what
like so how would we be in the future
how would we go about solving the root
of the problem because because to me
that the riots and this in the like
people being killed as a symptom of of
what like of
of racism being allowed of just massive
systemic racism honestly and how do we
get these [__] smarter than
like how do we who the people in charge
yeah well or the or the the cops who are
apparently unknowingly racist like well
first we got to stop minimizing black
lives matter you know all lives matter
and blue lives matter yet yes okay
we all are egalitarians they understand
that lives are important that's why
they're protesting but they're extremely
dismissive to the original cause because
you're like hey like my if
hypothetically like I'm an
african-american like I see people of my
like demographic being marginalized and
we make a movement called black lives
matter and you see a bunch of like just
like well-off other people say no all
lives matter that's extremely dismissive
and you're not actually looking at the
problem and then blue lives matter is
even more egregious cuz you're like you
know what's not happening you know
there's not a lot of young black men
going and killing police officers all
the time you know what is happening
police officers are killing a lot of
young African men it's the second
leading cause of death and black men
under 30 police violence so I mean and
it's just like why would you do if
you're an african-american you would be
terrified getting pulled over you'd be
terrified especially in these places
dude I am and I'm not I I hate I do not
like the police they're not they're not
public servants how they should be
they're not trained well they give them
way too much fire like why are we
militarizing the police you know they
serve like white why why is that the
thing yeah we they have they have like
the you know at some point like so think
about it shows you the weird position
that we put police officers in so many
ways and I'm not at all defending the
the police officer he points to
everything but but I'm just so I'm just
thinking about the school playground
situation during the kovat there's a mom
and a daughter playing at the playground
and a police officer has to get out of
his car and yeah say hey guys you got to
leave this part of me that gets it but
there's part of me
it's like like his job could be utilized
in such a different way than this
they're there following orders right but
I don't know maybe there's a spirit of
the law versus rule of the law kind of
concept so it's like if you you don't go
100 percent by the book
you go by your gut to some degree so
there's a there's a story it was in New
York there was a dude selling hot dogs
and a cop came up it's like hey man like
you like earns own for here like I'm
like I'm not gonna I'm not gonna do
anything about it but I'm gonna come
back later would you just plead please
be gone so I don't have to in this man
he had his hands behind his back because
I mean he was like fallen on hard times
and like was just gonna shoot this guy
if he was gonna arrest him and he didn't
because the guy handled it just like by
the spirit of the wall like hey like
this is just kind of unsafe but it's not
really affecting anyone go ahead and
leave so like cops really just have like
this massive Authority and whenever you
give people power they just they will
use it inherently so if you just let
cops like that like laws are in place to
keep people safe to some degree right
hypothetically if we had less
by-the-book people and more spear of the
law cops I think it would be a lot
different but so then then so look at
situations like in our own town with
Justin Derosier I mean he responded to a
call and it was just a you know some
sort of I don't know setup or something
like in in so he if he's walking in with
the spirit of the law like I'm giving
these people now if any was so it sucks
because like one wrong player wrong one
bad player is enough to like give that
whole spirit that that police have to
work with of like hey come on guys get
out of here like you know that I don't
know [__] we're just talking about like
how to fight evil the kind of evil I
will say this I being a police officer
is a none M people position Oh God
because indefinitely I would say
probably most cops are good people
everything most people are good ID well
I think almost all people are good at
their core they just either up and
mislead
some degree or not but like the problem
like with the police stuff is it's it's
a Brotherhood like they they cover each
other so when you get one really shitty
racist guy out of 99 and that dude that
dude [__] up like they just cover it
like that's why this riot happened
because they didn't prosecute the dude
who did it they just started firing
people and are going to talk about it
if they would have just like prosecuted
this man and show that they were going
to like abide by the law that they
should be abiding by it like this man
murdered this guy right on duty like
unjustly he was trained not to that he
did it anyways he's got a history of
doing this so it's like it needs to come
from inside police forces like they got
us and it's not easy because like if you
you're the one do that stands up you're
just gonna get shunned out so it's like
this um it's almost like a cult you know
like you can't you can't speak out yeah
I mean so I mean the the human error in
this it just seems like we're gonna have
so many more reasons to have some sort
of like [__] drone police force a
society I'm making a jump but I mean I
do think that I don't know next 10 years
max I mean I see but robots can't buy by
the spirit of law though right that's
the thing is gonna be a problem it's
even worse than this now because they
just say you're breaking a law this is
how I act so I would do not want to take
the human element out of police that's
the last I don't barely want police to
be the thing but but I think that we're
going to have so much [__] to wear
but we're gonna get to a point where
people are in my Keanu probably is the
best option or something and it's gonna
be bad it's not it's not a good thing I
just don't know I mean like what like
what else can we do like how do we make
our how do we make our police force
better with actually being like
intelligent and civilized and and you
know equal across the board because you
know the the police academy in you know
Rhode Island is not the same in
Minneapolis or whatever like I'm gonna
at least I don't think I don't know
exactly how it all works but I don't
know it yeah it's gonna start with
training
really just better training I've seen
video like I've really dive deep into
this and I've seen the training videos
that they show people like they hire
third party or parties to train their
cops just for some police forces and
they're just really highly militarized
that a lot and some police officers have
like a like a fetishization of like Navy
SEALs and wanting to be like an operator
and being the guy and breaking in the
door like you saw it a couple weeks ago
they broke into this man's house not in
police uniforms shot his girlfriend shot
20 times he shot back he's getting if
he's going to federal prison because of
it they broke in to the wrong house he's
not a criminal mm-hmm so you know what
an ABC would never do like the start is
information when today when you hear
about the seals break in the wrong house
you don't like like real military ops
they know for sure you know that this
person's in there and this is the right
house you got a job and you do it very
well so your riling these people up
you're given them too much firepower and
you're telling them to go be an operator
and they want they'd like to be that guy
they've seen all the movies you know
they've seen like what is it like
American soldier a lone soldier like all
the the war propaganda that like really
feta sighs like this overt force right
but they're not trained to and I do
think a lot of it comes from that and
then also this is just a side note the
police are inherently there just to
protect so if corporations own the
government and government makes the laws
and they hire the police all the laws
are gonna be in favor of these people so
you know who doesn't go to jail anyone
on Wall Street anyone that commits like
way more like into the stood forward to
check a target for 200 bucks probably
even if he did it might not have been
forged you have like investment bankers
inside trading for millions of dollars
like they look there's just way worse
crimes that go on but they're just
white-collar right so but they don't you
know please Hearn they're not blowing
their doors open you know it's it just
seems it's a way to oppress movements to
some degree like it's just the
watchdog's of the status quo it's like
that's why so on this hypothetical
alright so your work you're you want a
business yeah you want a big business
your workers decide that they're tired
of you taking a
of them in reaping more benefit from the
so they make their labor provides you
give them materials their labor makes
your stuff more valuable you sell it for
a premium but you don't pay them a lot
so they are like hey man we're trying to
get we're tired again shafted we're
gonna band together in a strike and they
pick up the phone and they're like they
call the police and I'm like hey you
better come get these people in line so
they just protect the status quo to
something like this is just a watchdog
of the establishment and that's why I
inherently don't like police even
without all the racial stuff it's okay
so when you say that when you say that
the way that like it's though I mean the
whole world understands is we identify
with our jobs and so like there's this
like instant like this one wrong but
like across America right now I bet you
in any police officer is maybe like 1%
closer to like being a little more
afraid of their life and themselves yeah
I would be too if I saw something I
don't envy cops at all not even a little
bit no I know and it's such a [__]
difficult weird conversation to have I
mean I just I try to think I try to say
okay here's the situation and like [__]
what can we do about it not like I know
everything about I don't know [__] about
it really I just think that it's it is a
big deal I think that if we're like
burning [__] police stations and make
you know riots it's it's going it could
uptick something big like you know we're
not immune to war we're not immune to
like an internal war there's already a
culture war happening on Twitter it's
just like there's a massive divide and
how people feel yeah and I mean what's
the boiling point because it seems like
there's like something new like this
every every few months every few weeks
there's something is it the media is is
this one person I think of this the
media because like I said earlier I
really think that people are inherently
good and intelligent and people are just
mislead with like so it's just every
corporate media station is it just mega
propaganda one side or the other so you
are just it causes division and I don't
know if you've like looking into a man
named Noam Chomsky mm-hmm okay so Noam
Chomsky's thing is um
it's uh something about consent but it's
a term and it's basically so Americans
political spectrum is like very close
together but you owe manufacturing
consent you make one side look extreme
and the other look extreme but they're
both really close together and you make
people feel like there's no ideas
outside of that so then you make people
like if you look at what the two parties
agree on
it's almost everything it's like guns
abortion and immigration and that's it
that's the only three things that they
can't end on and it's kind of just like
this circus fake wrestling kind of thing
and they just tell you you're either on
this side or this side but they agree on
hundreds of things and you don't really
get to choose so they pit everyone
against each other and they don't get
mad at any real problem you're not this
then you're that yes so they give you a
[__] that's a good example with some
chunks noam chomsky why my noam chomsky
like they give you eight it's like a yes
or no question when yes or no it's not
the answer that you have like it's like
what if you're not blue than you're red
or whatever it's it's it's weird but we
don't understand that we're looking at
things through that lens so what what's
what's next so at so after in a world
where which is right now ninety percent
of the news that everybody sees is from
six different [__] companies I think
it's less than that actually and that's
the sad part
okay so in a world where that's what's
going on I mean the media whoever
controls the media has the power that's
just you you control the narrative you
control the gated institutional
narrative as Eric Weinstein says and
what's after this like what's a where
you know everybody realizes like hey
this is [__] up we can't do this
of course there's like an up you know
some uprising like this sucks riots
whatever what's after that Spencer
what's like how can we not [__]
everything up so bad um what's after
that so once people realize I mean I
think dude people already have mastered
I think we're there
that's the thing is like but the problem
is we're still playing teams we all have
the same problems and they both pinpoint
that and they give you a different
solution and then they just force you to
fight against each other we're already
here there's already a massive distrust
of government news all of it everyone's
[__] sick of it like we're at a
boiling point 100% and all that needs to
happen is
is we need to unify so so the Hunger
Games so a view have you seen those
movies
read the books yeah seen movies yeah so
in the end where it's essentially like
turn your weapons to the Capitol you
know like that's essentially it's it so
are we the best is is region to the best
is region three the best like that's
what's been happening and we're at this
point where we're like we're all looking
at each other all the twelve factions or
whatever or the twelve whatever and
we're like hey guys it's not like we
don't even want to fight each other
we're talking about the same [__] so so
this is gonna be a [__] up sense but who
is the it was the person we aim the
arrow at I guess in the in the end here
like who is the who is the
behind-the-scenes shadow that's like
[__] who's who's the puppet master
well it's [__] ass I mean
corporations on the government but the
federal government these are our public
servants that we vote in so if you can
uncheck people I mean this is so
demeaning to say that people get tricked
into voting for people against their own
like good good intentions right but the
news is so you have people have such
poor information that they do I mean you
see a like a lot of sites like
right-wing populism so like Trump he
finds a bunch of problems like he's like
hey like jobs are going all these things
are happening you know but instead of
we're outsourcing and doing all these
things and we're allowing big
corporations to exist in other countries
it's Mexicans are taking your jobs so
you found a real problem you did but now
you force a narrative so like that and
that's how like a lot of things take off
I don't think Donald Trump is the
problem I think he's a symptom of a
problem right when the thing about the
forced narrative now is you could find
the people who are going to believe it
like if you look at I think that a lot
of the world isn't you're currently
aware of like theta like the Internet
the the people Google and [__] they know
so much more about you than you know
about yourself like they they know so
much about you so that when you're
running on when you're running for
president like a lot of the reason why
Donald Trump won is
it's a narrow statement but a lot of the
reason is because they found the right
people who are going to vote so they
know it's like who believes in these
things where they act like let's feed
them as they watch YouTube as they're
watching these things on their phone is
they're on Facebook as they're scrolling
through and we know that they're the
type to vote for me and believe in these
things
based off of their data that we've
gotten from all of their searches from
all of the things that they bought at
Target because we own the credit company
credit card companies to you like all
this [__] that they have on these people
they're able to directly feed to the
right people - yeah so but but so those
people are essentially they're kind of
suckers like they're not suckers they're
being made to look like suckers like
they're their choices and what they're
arguing about is like like it's not that
you're wrong or right it's like why are
you [__] arguing about that what do
you look around you your reality is not
that what are you talking about
so there's a lot of this like being fed
things by people who want you to believe
or be mad about the things that they
believe and are mad about yeah look at I
mean look at the paradigm between CNN
and Fox News you know they're both
making you mad about something it's just
the opposite thing but it's the same
problem like that's the thing like you
need to be mad at outsourcing definitely
like all these movements just find a
real problem like as Americans we all
have really similar problems no matter
where you live I mean it's different in
the city to the rural areas yeah but
like jobs people are scared about jobs
so if if somebody comes up and says hey
this these people that look like this
are the problem it like it gives you
agency to like and PARP analyze that
you're like oh okay I have a summary I
have a distinct enemy that's causing all
my strife in these are causing the
problems and they also trick you into
caring about [__] you don't care about -
that you shouldn't care about like a lot
of these problems like I mean abortion
is definitely like that's an ethical
choice and yeah
that one's not people really do care
about that it's a rough that's a hard
one to figure out we haven't even have
to humanity figured that one out no area
and humans do really bad wherever
because there's not a line but dude I
have to close that window cuz it
pressure washer try be crazy okay
what we do about it we do about you
matter I mean all this what we can do at
this moment is we could take the Jordan
Peterson approach and just concentrate
on ourselves sort of thing so how do we
how do people as individuals Mike and
not you know I'm jumping from how do we
solve this as humanity just because I
think that it's good to talk about with
each other and I think that I think that
we shouldn't be afraid as just any any
everyday people to discuss these things
like man what do you think about it like
just you you know we get so caught in
arguments and like you know putting
ourselves in our own anger and our own
beliefs in these situations that we miss
out on being able to just talk about
them as like okay hmm
you know what wandering out wondering
about them without ever fully like
believing or settling in a position so
encourage anybody to just think about
like what's next for Humanity or like
what what would be better than what
we're doing right now not just on an
individual level but like what you know
just wonder aloud with your friends and
try to have more of an intellectual
conversation but also on an individual
level Spencer what could we do you know
the typical watch less news the typical
like how can we how can we help each
other and and help ourselves on like an
individual well with the situation
thinking with politics is I think people
start in the wrong spot you can't start
with news because they will force you to
have an opinion but if you start with
political philosophy and do a lot of
reading okay start with regular
philosophy figure out how you feel about
a Galit arianism how other people's
lives matter how you feel about the
world around you like what is reality
like all these things that are really
important and like building a worldview
start there and then if you actually
just go from Socrates all the way up
you'll just start hitting political
philosophy like you'll hit Hegel Marx um
Herbert yet Herbert Spencer which is a
capitalist philosopher like you'll just
hit him because philosophy just leads to
politics because that's just the end
road that's where you apply this
philosophy so if you can develop a
worldview before you get tricked by CNN
you're way more immune to it because
you're like hey I know how I feel about
stuff and how I want the world around me
to look so you are you have this you're
sniff test it's amazing your skepticism
is just way higher than it normally
would be and it's just really helpful
for your life anyways to get in
philosophy it was one of the single most
enjoyable and helpful things I've ever
done right it is it's a it's one of my
favorite things like I absolutely love
it but it's it's a such a huge thing
that like I stumbled in because I was
looking for mental health and inevitably
me to try and take care of yourself you
same same with you - yeah yeah dude it's
like you start learning about the world
around you and you start to learn like
where you fit in it and how you can fit
in it and what we've done in in the past
I mean like learning about history is
some freaking finished yet but sapiens
you've all y'all know Harare but like
learning about that like it changes my
worldview I remember actually I watched
a [__] documentary the one with Will
Smith it's on Netflix one strange rock
how did you watch that one
I remember watching it and I was like
also you know reading all this stuff but
it like that documentary changed like my
outlook like seeing these like super
high def photos of the earth and
understanding how like diatoms work in
how like like really really getting the
[__] backbone behind like hey the
trees give you oxygen without them
you'll [__] die like like really
understanding how everything is is one
planet and how it keeps us alive when it
changes your perspective and it also it
seems weird to think like watching a
documentary about the earth and the
planet is enough to change your
political views but it is so I think I
agree with Spencer get [__] smart
dude like learn learn don't just argue
with these narratives learn a better way
to see narratives yes so there I mean
what do you all say go meta go Matt I'm
stuck in it I can't you know deserve the
third point perspective on viewpoints so
you can't you can't just show up into
politics and start watching CNN and
they're just gonna tell you something
that makes you vote for them that's it
that's what's happening they wants you
to vote for them they're gonna tell you
a bunch of talking points that you can
throw at people that they disagree with
but you didn't so just going back to
Chomsky your
okay so if the pit of the political
spectrum is like a hundred inches long
American politics is two inches like
it's just real close together so you
haven't looked at so many ideas that you
might really like and I'm not saying I
like that I engage in a lot of political
discourse with people that don't agree
with me just on reddit there's a
subreddit called our slash political
compass and it's a it's a graph so it's
four quadrants so it's two axis and set
of left-right and I talk to people that
don't agree with me at all all the time
and it's one of the best ways to
understand someone's worldview and even
if you really disagree with them you at
least learn how to deal with their ideas
better so do not insulate yourself from
other people's ideas and go find a bunch
of people that agree with you and then
hole up and go listen because in worst
case scenario you figure out why those
ideas are bad and how you can make your
ideas better and I think in the midst of
this a lot of times you know something I
always try to improve on is like how he
did you get how like when you're
discussing them because sometimes you
will stumble across stuff where it's
like oh I do feel strongly about this
and I do actually know quite a bit you
know like police brutality make me kind
of mad I'm not gonna lie right but but
you also have the ability to just see
like your time at reddit comments I see
them digress so [__] quickly it hurts
me which is I mean it's hilarious
because the smart people like jump away
from the knuckleheads and by that I mean
like right out people who are just like
all of a sudden they had different views
and they're like [__] you bro your mom's
so stupid it's like what yeah you just
ad hominem attack yeah so I think also
you know I observe observe the way I
learned by watching other people in and
learning about them and then running
that through the filter of me so I watch
a lot of people like my dad for example
he's very exuberant and loud and being
what he talks about stories and he'll be
telling about this story where he's just
telling you that he walked into the the
grooming shop and there was a yellow
Labrador you know he's telling you that
story but it's this long and he's like
you know he's just all big and he's
he'll lean into your face and he's so
he's telling that story and it's it's
you know he's a storyteller and it's
great but when we're passionate about
things that maybe were disagreeing with
someone
we accidentally sometimes talk at people
like it like mom I used my dad as
example because he's exuberant he
doesn't try to be but if he was talking
passionately he'll start putting his
finger in your face and stuff and he
doesn't see that he's like bringing it
to a position where a majority of people
seventy five percent of people sitting
across the table from him are gonna be
an uncomfortable they don't really have
the combo anymore because it's like
you're like yelling at me I wasn't
trying to debate I was just kind of
wondering what you thought about this
and we can maybe compare our Diaz I'm
not saying like be calm if you're not a
calm person but just be aware of when
you're having these conversations like
every time the other person starts
talking maybe let out a belly breath man
like just like okay that relax my
shoulders call my eyebrows like these
are kind of overly obvious things but I
think that a lot of us get so caught up
in talking to each other instead of with
each other we can we can form a third we
can form a third like you know Metta
look at the problem when you just
combine and allow each other to both
have like a calm input so not everyone
that you talk to you is gonna be good
faith you know sometimes they just want
to [__] on you and you gotta realize
when that's happening but never going to
in conversation thinking that the
biggest important thing that I could say
and this is not I I am good at this but
most people aren't it's really
frustrating for me to talk to people I'm
close to like family members about
politics they're not listening to me
mm-hmm but I'm give I'm giving a lot of
effort to try to understand their point
and they're not giving any effort to
understand mine which if they're trying
to win an argument they immediately win
because you're like okay yes I see what
you're saying but then they don't do
that with you they don't even take your
ideas into consideration it's very
frustrating and no one learns so like
you're never gonna learn anything you
don't listen to people yeah and even if
they've got ideas that you don't agree
with listen to him anyways because they
help temper your worldview let's talk
about listening like like let's let's
break the glass
listening like like after a while you
are unaware that you're looking at each
other's eyes you're unaware it's like
this conversation we start out in
certain areas we like wander off
and we glanced over but when you're
listening how do we how do we explain
listening because I think that I was
want to blame social media in phones but
I think that there's this weird for a
long time I would think that I was
listening even though with my right hand
I'm like oh sending up that text and go
but what I would be doing a lot of the
times is I was listening but kind of
selectively it wasn't on purpose
but I think that our attention spans
jump to jump farther outside of the
conversations in it's like okay what are
you jumping to are you trying to be
right are you trying to contribute to
the conversation as you're talking to
someone looking them in the eyes
hearing what they're saying what are you
saying to yourself in your head are you
in also in your body language are you
going mMmmm are you shaking your head
are you going okay are you acting
accidentally kind of body language and
contempt I'm just you know another
strange thing to point out but I think
that becoming aware of our body language
and how we're listening
like what's actually happening when
you're listening what is listening how
do I do it how can I do it better
because I think that little kind of [__]
is a lot of like what's what's going
wrong with a lot of these conversations
conversations are escalating to
arguments and debates and so all we want
to do because we don't want to step on
each other's feelings or like feel
uncomfortable we just [__] meme fi
everything and we short sentence
everything and we just like say
catchphrases to each other sometimes
like I think that conversations are more
important than that
yeah and we're deflecting discomfort too
I would say just get out there and start
debating people start argue who don't
agree with its debating and I'm not
saying isn't like a rhetoric not to it
to like be not to win but to just have a
discussion because there is a flow of
you say something I counter you say
something I counter I say something you
counter that it's just inherently part
of talking about things that are more
than like how was your day so like
debating is fine it just you've got to
be receptive and you can't just because
it's so hard to be really clear and all
your ideas that you feel really good
about and then have somebody not agree
with you
you don't have any rebuttals and I think
that's what really happens you say
something you think is like this is part
of your worldview you really agree with
and someone's like no and they're like
well and then they say X Y & Z and then
you don't have a response to X Y & Z so
you feel uncomfortable so then you mean
if I so right right there yeah that's
like a [__] error like we need to put
like a 404 there's something wrong here
and then you get that little pit and you
start breathing quick and you can't
think and then you just don't display
one you don't display your ideas how you
want it to and to the conversation
devolves so I would say really well
getting go read what logical fallacies
are and go read through them and then
try to pick out when people do them to
you because when they make a lot of bad
ones you can understand when they're
being not good faith they're being bad
faith actor and they're just trying to
stifle you and then just get into
philosophy I didn't know this was ants
for the other thing but getting into
philosophy really helps you parse
through really floaty
topics in general like a political
theory religion like any of these things
that are big no knows like having an
objective epistemological view just it
really helps weed through it because
then you you're sniff test is good like
you can smell the [__] if it's
really coming you can tell when people
are just trying to like defer you away
from a topic right in go ahead and it's
just it's not always about winning I
mean really get it out of your head that
you're trying to win you're trying to
understand this person and most
importantly if you make a good effort
for them to understand them they might
understand you and you maybe change
their mind about something you're never
gonna change about everything but if you
attack them you're not gonna convince
them of anything right you really just
want them to be more sympathetic to you
so when they see people like you they're
not going to be so vile right yeah and
you can formulate new ideas together
like it doesn't have to be like oh
here's what I learned and I want to
prove that it's right or wrong it's it's
like what like what if they have what if
they read the other half of what you did
on that there there's a podcast called
stuff you should know how stuff works
and those two they basically like us
research their own areas of the internet
like and they come back and they are
like on the subject and they come back
and they discuss it not like I'm more
right than you they discuss like oh
here's what I found about that oh oh
that's crazy Chuck I didn't read about
that part that is very incredible so you
learn about a subject together and I
think that's super available for
everybody in their everyday
I just want people to get better at
conversations so we were talking earlier
about conspiracy theory which we're
gonna jump to after one more suggestion
philosophize this on YouTube I think
that's a good place to start did you
ever go onto that channel that YouTube
channel I've listened to everything one
of those podcasts yeah dude it's a great
place start because I think you know we
learn about philosophy I think I hope
that people's brains don't go well I
need to go to the library and I need to
check out Socrates and I mean you knew
that too but also maybe listen to my
podcast as well right yeah well well but
I mean getting people lending your hand
down and pulling them up off the ground
getting them started like just don't
overthink it go to YouTube and start to
listen to these in the morning and
they'll kind of make you think about the
world a little bit differently and if
you're in college like if you're going
to school go take a philosophy class
please do that it's been the most and so
taking humanities classes I've taken
every single humanities class at the
Community College and it was the most
enriching thing that I've ever done for
me in academia it's changed me forever
like the way I look at the world the way
I think about things like it was very
very awesome and I highly recommend it I
I would love to do that I am a little
concerned with my attention span
sometimes I I mean I love this subject
though so I feel like I would probably
be able to pay attention the teacher the
professor that does most of them is the
only like academic person that has ever
actually affected my actual life yes
like give her a million hugs she's one
of my favorite people shot her name her
name is Mary leach at LCC like if you
can go take one her classes she is one
of most excellent professors ever I
really really enjoyed her and all my
close friends she's their favorite
teacher too she's just awesome I highly
recommend it oh yeah guys check out
philosophy Spencer what do you think
about conspiracy theories what is
conspiracy theory when is it invented
what do you know about MKULTRA dude oh
okay actually a lot and that's a good
way to start so conspiracy theories have
evolved they used to be like as Bigfoot
real blah blah blah stuff like that like
oh they're aliens and then JFK
assassination all stuff like that but I
think well right-wing media does
actually just pedal a lot
of conspiracies like a massive amount
like that side of the news media is just
always on top of it our president does
it it's like a lot of people in
authority positions do it and I think
the reason conspiracies are getting so
popular is because you know lefties have
realized that we don't really have a lot
of control in society and like there's
no grand plan and everything is just
chaos and if there's a lot of nihilism
but people that will need more right
this is obviously a massive
generalization like one of the
right-wing values is like personal
liberty freedom solidarity like I want
to be my own agent in the world and I
want like I can do all these things like
I have the power of my own life so that
inherently draws you to these grand
narratives that explain something that
like would insinuate that there's a
master plan there's something in control
and I'm the one that figured it out so
it gives you it gives you agency over
the world of some degree because there's
the thing that you can change there's
like once we pull this linchpin it's the
way and it's just because the world is
so hectic a narrative is very helpful JP
talks about narratives all the time it's
how we parse through a lot of things I
mean I don't actually agree with a lot
of philosophy but he we do use a
narratives to describe a lot of things
and these narratives are really
convincing to people and it makes them
feel like there's Liberty like there
solidarity in the world and people get
attached to them and then they attach
their idea identity to them and then
they find a bunch of people that believe
that and now like oh I'm an activex or
I'm a flat earther
stuff like that but I really just think
it's a it's just a symptom of that well
so so when we say conspiracy theories
there's through in my head I think you
know like CIA and aliens and in the
government and UFOs but I also think of
you know like like Epstein in like the
[__] Clintons killing everybody I
think those are just beyond cancer does
that just happens I mean you're like
well so well but that's the thing is
it's all being thrown into so conspiracy
theory the the terminology I think it
was after JFK the assassination like it
was essentially - there's there's some
sort of proof somewhere
that I can't pull out of my butt right
now but there's some sort of something
somewhere that says conspiracy theory
was actually invented after I think the
JFK assassination to actually diverge
people away from Michael look away sort
of it was this thing made up by the
government the word and so it's kind of
like a way to disperse crazy people like
like so so if like oh you're just a
conspiracy theorist so it's a good way
to brush off people and not make it a
serious conversation but so how do we
because because what I think I'm saying
is is there's [__] importance in like
conspiracy theories because like there
has to be a ground just like comedians
have they're the ones who find the edge
of like hey we're taking this thing too
seriously we're gonna kill each other if
we don't laugh about it because
seriously theories are almost like hey
this is like these people are really
good at this corruption we need to help
that or there's no there's an important
spot for a conspiracy theory in the
society it frustrates a colony because
people so it's usually considered to
start with something that might be drawn
like 5% and then people paint a whole
narrative behind it so like I don't
understand why people have to dig so far
to feel like the government is doing in
scrupulous things like they'd tell you
that they're doing them you know like
they told us the war in Iran was
unjustified like it they told us about
MKULTRA like they're just telling us the
[__] they're doing like why do you even
have to dig like you can just see it my
favorite one that's recent is Bill Gates
is going to use the vaccine to put
microchips in you to track you but you
know what people carry around all the
time
GPS is with microphones and they're
called cell phones and you obligatory
give away your rights to have one so
like what seized so they just don't use
a skeptical eye on all these things like
they don't there's no reason that just
they just take this narrative off and
run with it but the problem is the
government gives people no leeway and
because they do a bunch of shitty things
and of course that might be true so it's
like I one thing I do like conspiracies
though is they make people really
skeptical of the government and which
you need to be I'd rather have a
population of conspiracy theory as being
all loony rather than people that are
really subservient do you see a world
where when we talk about the government
they wear
we feel a sense of trust because now
it's like I'm gonna trust the government
as much as I trust the [__] media and
it's like I don't know
you know it's an uncomfortable feeling
for people in a society to realize like
oh there's not someone who's ultimately
looking out for me they're looking out
for like their plan for what gives them
to most not only money in their pocket
but I think I think it gets to a point
with these people I think humans are so
impressive and they can like train their
brains to be such a [__] machine that
there's so many people who it's not like
they're just trying to get more mimosas
and more islands and more Ferraris I
don't think it's that I think that it's
like they're so like the the roots are
just so deep and like dug into like what
they're doing that they're so detached
from I don't know do you see a world
where we trust the government say no and
I hope we never do yeah never I hope
that the you know what the governor
should always be scared of their people
we should always hold people in power
accountable they serve us that's why
they're there so so when it comes to
when it comes to things like not
specifically ubi but like that would be
like the start of like this one war
health government there's so [__]
dangerous like okay there's like
separate I I think that those things
trip over each other so if we were
trying to lean towards I think that
we're at such a dissolving distrust for
our governments like not only in America
but like just everywhere like it's like
Western democracy is just collapsing
essentially right okay so
how do is it okay the reason why I said
one world government is because I think
that the only thing that could come
after this is like realize how far
advanced we are with technology how
connected we really are how we have to
take action about you know the global
warming like all these things it seems
like what's coming is a we've all got it
bound together but also with that let's
all bound together there might be some
sort of like one [__] government or
you know I'm not trying to sound hippy
and conspiracy theory what I say one
one-world government I'm literally just
saying like more than just there's gonna
be these nationalist views like it's
okay Eric is still gonna exist but I
think there's gonna be something that's
kind of I mean that's kind of what I
mean look at the banks they already are
that but they're all [__] corrupt no
but they already do just sit above
everything like the banking system in
general is very ubiquitous like this is
why conspiracy theories run off because
is there a hint of truth to like this
probably cabal that kinda it does they
don't robably don't sit in some shady
dim lit room planning out the world but
there definitely is people that have a
lot of power that reaches through every
major country and every major power that
probably do we call some shots and do
control money I mean because at the end
of the day it is just like controlling
the circulation of money what I will say
is though like authoritarian governments
like well we are authoritarian
government China Russia they don't get
along historically they want to impose
their rule they want no infringement on
it so we will never really have a
unified government it will never happen
because I mean the incentive of I mean
we're national like national pride like
we're Americans we're not gonna be we're
not part of China
we're not that you know the Russians are
extremely nationalistic so is China like
all these really hyper military like
Iran like we're all other than the fact
that China technically is a communist
regime like they are very totalitarian
they've got a big police state same with
Russia like we're very similar to them
other than our economic platform like
we're now getting along it's not gonna
happen ever I really doubt it I mean if
anything one will conquer the other but
I don't think that ubi is gonna be the
start of that I actually think
I think that it's a good idea like why
like why shouldn't people get them
unlike if we're gonna bail out the
cruise line industry that banks offshore
and doesn't pay taxes why would you not
give people money like if we're the
richest nation to ever live ever in the
history of forever and we spend 75
percent of our budget on military even
like why can't people stop starving I
would feel great you know like Wyatt why
if your grandma gets cancer you have to
file bankruptcy but we buy bombs and
bail out the cruise line industry you
know our priorities are a little misstep
no because you know what curing
grandma's cancers and make money and
that's what it comes down to and that
feels bad and that's why maybe burna
downs not terrible the problem is that
chaos ensues more chaos and every
uprising has led an authoritarian
government because they have the means
to take over after you topple something
because there's a lot of instability but
then we also come to the problem of
where if we do it really slowly
you get one president in who's on the
other side that doesn't want it who
undoes the last eight years of progress
so like where are we at like you can't
do it slow like like there's this
liberal fantasy of like incremental
change but it just goes away I don't see
how we have just one [__] like
how do like you do that the president
thing is just so dorky like well I mean
I don't know what like again it's an
it's an undesirable spot it's just like
we're talking about police officers like
I don't know the answer but I can see
that like what we're doing doesn't seem
to be working out mm-hmm now what a okay
imagine this conversation we're having
this conversation we're curious about
the government blah blah but we were in
China imagine like do something I want
to I want to point out because I don't
think that people understand what's like
also going on in China too or maybe I
don't think that any of us do in America
so actually so that's the thing yeah so
what if every image we're seeing of
China is completely like just [__]
made up by the media well I'm sure to
some degree like go to art /sy know or
see no it's a pro China sub and it's
just very interesting to see the other
point of view because I undead so we are
having an economic war with them so
everything all the footage that we see
you
all of it is just very forced through a
narrative and I'm not I don't like
authoritarianism like I'm a libertarian
to some degree I'm just a libertarian
left not right so I don't realize
capitalism either but they they're of an
authoritarian police state and so are we
so like yeah I mean I just point out
because it's like so so if it's true I'm
just I think it's it's important to
watch like what they're doing we may end
up doing do you think yeah you I don't
know if you've been on Twitter yet today
No okay those pictures of the Hong Kong
like press yeah like taking pictures of
police officers and they're just
allowing them and they arrested a CNN
reporter this morning so we might
sometimes be a little more authoritarian
than China mm-hmm I just think that we
get really conflated with America is
like this very free ubiquitous nation
where you do whatever you want I don't
know man China's pretty interesting
though like I would love to be a fly on
the wall and figure out just what uh
like what really goes on there because
they did have the greatest growth and
economic power and standard of living of
any country to ever live in like 35
years I think it's it's unprecedented
and I mean I've seen reports of like if
you're I mean they oppress the [__] on
minorities but I mean so do we so like
we redline districts and that they've
got a really really high standard of
living in a lot of places they really
take care of people that are native-born
so what about so I've seen their like
they have like a prism at camps that
[__] over there right now
yeah that's not acceptable like that's
I'm saying they like really oppressed
before so that's the hard thing is it's
like hard to know I mean and again it's
not like it is hard for our brains when
like even when we talk about things like
okay I saw this like was that all of
China is that like a bunch of bad actors
like is that is that like the Joe Biden
of China that is doing the the you know
bad [__] like you know I mean like it's
so hard for our brains
to conceptualize because you know we
can't juggle all this [__] craziness
we don't know what's actually true when
we're reading it but it's it we want to
watch it and we want to see like oh oh
hey what's going on over there because
we don't want that to happen to us
because I think that you know look at
like the technology that they're going
to start implementing over there is
obviously going to trickle over to where
were using we're using like facial
recognition and stuff over there to
charge people if they jaywalk sort of
things like you know that could be our
reality but they've just granted police
access to facial recognition in
Washington yeah really
so dude it's happening like this is why
you got to keep government in check like
we the people are powerful we got a band
together because writing this we cannot
allow a police like a real police date
to happen or we but the problem is were
sold that we're Americans were free were
sold this narrative that we are the
freest country were the best country we
have the most Liberty but we're actually
getting police stated and we're killing
minorities right but but yes so the
narrative they use is like hey they're
taking away your freedoms and they're
like well no I'm [__] free they don't
do that to me and then you're right it's
it's a narrative that they feed you to
spark you in certain ways yes and both
sides do it and so like Trump passed
some some very unscrupulous
authoritarian bills like and just for
tracking like for gun rights like there
were red flag laws he slipped in another
bill so like this one thing like I think
you people guns like I know gun violence
is a massive problem and we should
probably regulate them better not more
but having an armed populace like i alt
Amit Lee I'm the most scared of the
government at the end of the day like so
but he even the right who's supposed to
not gun snatch gun snatch more than
Obama people just don't read the bills
so like they're all taking away rights
all the rights you think they're
protecting there's this natural way and
until we can like just come together and
like say hey stop it and like we're
unified people which the media won't
allow us to do it's just gonna get worse
and worse until we have like what Hong
Kong is right now well I think people
just just being aware trying to be aware
try to realize like oh are my opinions
just from the media like how much
how much am I actually mad about this
what are my actions here how can we
communicate this better do I know do I
just like a slot machine is designed to
make you sit down longer and get the
wins and spend more money and put more
quarters in social media in the news is
made to get you to keep on clicking man
to keep on staying on there so the it's
a runaway train
it's a runaway train and get the [__]
off the tracks like look around and do
your own research in come together yeah
and if you can build a philosophical
base or an ideological base no one will
ever trick you out of it you know you
can change your ideas but you're never
getting tricked by anyone because you
know how you feel it's it's like
learning how to learn yes it's so it's
kind of like we were talking about with
health I think that's another important
thing with health is like okay yeah
you're gonna follow this diet you're
gonna do exactly what this thing wrote
down and like okay but if you're not
understanding it then you're gonna get
to your goal in 12 months you're gonna
get to your goal and you didn't look
great at that for that vacation but then
because you didn't learn how to take
care of your body properly you didn't
learn how if I'm not exactly following
this regimen that this piece of paper
says I if you don't know anything about
your body you're just gonna fall right
back on it so I think it's it's learning
how to learn like use the tools learn
how to really [__] use the tools
learn about new tools before you go into
the in to start building you know and
learn how to extrapolate data that's a
big thing is it's very easy to mislead
people with data is if you don't if you
just say 40% of this is this and people
look into it like you can make anything
say anything so you just have to be way
more thorough with how they got these
numbers like who's paying for these
numbers to be made in any way in any
form of study or data management like
just figure out where it's coming from
figure out where the biases and then
maybe you can see hey they're trying to
mislead me with this or hey this is good
data what the problem is
takes a lot of time it's very hard
mm-hmm and that people like either of
those things yeah I mean so that's the
thing is like we live in such a society
of headline reading I mean I'm so guilty
of it myself like it's impossible to not
like I will formulate I will in my head
argue the opinion that I formed just
from the art the headline of
article so I'll make this is messed up
but then I won't like it and I'll think
that in my head without reading through
it some people just are posting them
whatever but I think learning
mmm I pigeon-holed myself I would uh
yeah I would say well 70 to 80% of
people only read the headline mmm oh
okay I remember dad so think about
percentages anyway so think about when
we're looking at like we took this poll
well who were the people and where were
they and where did they live and what
there's like all these different things
like oh we we took a poll and 16 percent
of people said that they prefer this
well they only interviewed a hundred
people you know I mean in will for and
then we'll put that up against some like
peer-reviewed thing that reviewed a
hundred thousand people or something the
things that we look at percentages in
stats so I think you know Steven Pinker
is a good a good example this I haven't
actually read his books but have you
heard of Steven Pinker I've heard the
name essentially he's just like if you
look at percentages like oh we're
actually if you're looking at the optoma
like we're actually better than we've
ever been the way of living is blah blah
blah or this percentage higher in these
areas it's basically giving you two
things to look at to compare but life is
not just this or that life is so much
gray area yeah maybe were the best in
economy but like what about [__]
happiness what about people killing
themselves like what's going on with
that I think that we we compare and we
look at pigeonholes
or just double use that word for no
reason we look at what the media tells
us to look at
we don't really compartmentalize and sit
back and say like what is this data like
what does this mean this this
percentages what does that have to do
with the subject that I'm pursuing what
does this have to do with the why of
humanity I think yeah I guess just
running it back through the lens of
numbers not being afraid exactly what I
started with the economy's a good
example of being misled because having a
really on paper strong economy doesn't
actually translate to how people's lives
are and you could see this deck from one
picture on CNN three weeks ago Dow Jones
up 700 M unemployment rate up to 30%
same screen it's like well okay so all
these numbers like the stock market
isn't only good
indicator of how wealthy people are
doing and when you look at Oh our
stomachs are so high it's our the Dow
Jones is at 28,000 or like a record high
but you look at it we've had wage
stagnation since 1970 and you've got 30%
less buying power than your father would
with the same job 30 years ago okay it's
our people really doing better no
they're not they're not even if the
unemployment rate is low like that kid
that doesn't account for people that are
underemployed for education either so
it's like there's just like a massive
amount of factors that go into this one
number that they're selling you like
there's a lot of externalities that go
along with things and if you can sum up
a whole massive economic system and one
single number well you can and you
shouldn't believe that that that's the
truth yeah yeah yeah it's it's this this
smoking gun like this is such a typical
sentence a statement but that smoking
gun thing is like well no the percentage
of this and the Dow is this how is that
not better
clearly so-and-so has done the best for
our Bubba and you're like somebody's
doing Waldo somebody is sure but sure
like what what are you talking about
here like what do you win why are you
pigeon holing this comparison thank you
we just we need to start with why man
when you start with why and we ask
ourselves all these questions well and
you're gonna see a lot of bad data
coming out really soon because as the
economy starts coming back online it's
gonna be like GDP growth was 25 percent
this month well yeah no [__] we didn't
do any GDP for three months so if like
if you have a hundred percent of
something you take fifty percent away
your need a hundred percent of that new
thing to get back to 100 percent that
makes sense
because you're gonna need double what
you had so it's like numbered
percentages get really conflated when
you drop them down and bring them back
up so like let's say we drop 99 percent
and then we gain a hundred percent it's
at two it's not at a hundred yeah so
people you can be really misconstrued by
just percentages in general and
sometimes you got to look at raw numbers
yeah I mean either way but that's
inherent that's pretty misleading though
that example definitely is because it's
like 100 percent that's good can't be
higher than that right yeah they
simplify our shift for us like it's not
a good thing so I guess just don't be
don't be a sucker yeah don't
it'll be a day really hard though
because you can't know everything about
anything or you can't know everything
about everything and I'm definitely a
sucker sometimes you know yeah yeah like
my girlfriend is an aesthetician and I
don't know anything about skin like she
could fool me about anything anything
doesn't matter anything involves skin
I'm a sucker you got me I'll refer to
somebody else that knows more to me but
that's a good thing though so if you
have skin problems so you have skin
issues or just questions thinking back
hey you tell me about makeup
can you tell you about this it's
actually so nice because I don't have to
deal with it you know like having it I
like that to have experts around you
about stuff that isn't super interesting
to you but you can just refer to them
with your trust and I wish the news was
like that yeah that's B's it's so nice
it's like you just you already know this
tell me please yeah I texted my I have a
group message full of friends and
there's probably like five five of our
female friends and there I was like all
right girls my hair looks ridiculous how
do I make it not look like total [__]
but I do also don't want to do anything
like I was hoping for something to put
in it right after I get on the shower
and then I don't touch it and they gave
me that they told me exactly what to get
and it's all the Plex
I don't know anything about it but I put
it in my hair and it looks nice nice
yeah so when you go into experts dude
you can have a friend circle full of
experts so just just learn your [__] and
then you can combine your [__] with
other people [__] and that's a folk
community like a couple of my friends
just know a lot about computers and I
was like maybe I'll learn about it but
now I'll just ask them to do it no just
tell them about fitness and then we win
everyone wins
yes that's great yeah that's it's so
important um we're getting up here in
time you got a head out here pretty soon
let's send it off with neural Inc have
you have you watched the Elon Musk
episode with Joe Rogan do you know about
neural link within a year owner Oh link
yeah neural link yessir what's your
thoughts on this like did you see he's
like this is gonna you know it's what do
I think about a neural link oh I think
well there's new like he named off all
the [__] that it's gonna do it it's
within a year it's gonna be done so what
I think is well this is I mean just
riding I repeat like tabletop RPGs like
D and E but sci-fi versions you get in a
lot of sci-fi tropes like in a capital
society some people are gonna be able to
afford the brain chips that makes them
think better and then they can make more
money and now you have a bigger wealth
gap that's frightening the gap you get
somebody that and then they can
communicate essentially telepathically
so now you've got a race of people a new
race that can communicate without
talking perfectly like you know how
words fail you know like when I drove to
describe something and you don't know
what I'm talking about all the way I can
just send you exactly what I'm seeing
yep so now they can communicate better
silently and make more money because
they can think better and make better
rational decisions because they have a
computer in their brain while poor
people don't get to do that so I
honestly wouldn't I don't want it to
happen until you can make ubiquitous
until everyone can have and until
everyone can do it if they want because
it's gonna cost such a massive divide
and we already have such a big class
divide but unlike sci-fi nerd' do I
think it's the coolest [__] ever yeah
that is the coolest thing that I've ever
heard so I think I have this like this
intuition that Elon Musk is not evil
like there's a lot of people who are
just like he's a Bond villain he's just
a narcissist but I love him yeah I think
that he's awesome I don't know I think
that I think that he is going to try his
best to make sure that it gets to the
people who like II like II if he can get
it to poor people in different
third-world countries I think he just
might you know I have a more a less
optimist if you O'Neill a mosque I think
a lot of people did yeah well no but not
bleh is bad so at the end of the day he
is a billionaire and he's accrued a lot
of money and he that's what he does he
makes money and he's trying to do the
minimalist thing no he's like planning
on like selling his house and [__] I
will say I really like what he's doing
for technology Big Ups to you you were
making everyone's life better you're
trying to save the planet but he does
have some very catastrophic opinions on
other things that he's not an expert in
but since he is big smarty pants boy he
just goes and has all these opinions and
he's an authoritative force but it's
like hey if like I was a doctor like
would you talk to me about like
herbology or like plants see this is
where I don't know because there's so
many people who are I start to think
that some people are just good thinkers
like I think we should have people who
are really smart they've shown them
to be smart in they're good at
problem-solving without extreme bias I
don't know there's there's parts of me
that that think of that like just
because you don't have the degree
doesn't mean that your opinion isn't as
good doesn't mean that like the way that
you see the thing isn't as important I
don't know no but yeah I agree
I mean I don't think you need a college
degree to have good opinions you just
need to have good rational skills and
epistemological skills and you need to
be able to reason through things so what
so what I think I was hinting at is like
I think that his opinion is actually
like important like III I value his
opinion because he's such a smart
[__]
um you may have less experience I guess
but it's hard to to know but if you look
at somebody who's basically socially
inept because he's so smart and you tell
him to have a bunch of ideas on social
issues they might not be the best
through that's true yeah and that's kind
of what I was hitting that like a lot of
is like mmm social things are probably
not great and he also it just is a
narcissist that debt definitely and
that's fine he does the world a great
service and you can be narcissist
there's a lot of them and they do a lot
of worse things that he does but that
doesn't always lead to admitting your
own faults when you're wrong about
social things because your image of you
is a big smartypants boy genius and my
opinion is correct even though maybe you
have not taken the time to look at this
idea very much hmm well Spencer
it's been great I do want to say one
thing though after like all the
catastrophic talk about how the world is
going so historically I have a lot of
faith in humanity you know things have
just always gotten better even though if
we're in like a little setback period
over the course of time effort like more
people have had more freedom in more
rights over the thousands of years that
humans have been alive and I don't think
that that's gonna stop I think that
Goods gonna win and I think that like
all this bigotry and all these bad
things that are happening or slowly just
gonna it's gonna take a lot of work and
a lot of pushback but people are willing
to do that and it's just going to get
better and better
excellent excellent I agree man I think
so too I'm optimistic about the future
I'm curious it's it's it's gonna be
crazy I hope that we don't have open
there's not a bunch more bad before good
sort of thing but I
I'm optimistic about future of humanity
it only gets better all right
listener drink some water and if you
have a stretch today man what it like
what's wrong with you what are you doing
you [__] together in stretch a little
bit he's up bye-bye
you